Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1840-1849., 505 items. (Box 4-7)
    - Letters, 1842., 29 items. (Box-folder 4:54-82)
      - D. Howard, Washington, to C[harles] Campbell, 6 December 1842., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:80)
        Thanks for the numbers of The Statesman, one containing notice of sale of establishment. Disappointed in the income of the paper. Heard of a daily establishment in the Northwest.
      - Scott Burdsall, Owego, New York to Anna Burdsall, Rahway, New Jersey, 22 December 1842., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:81)
        Goes sleigh riding.
      - C[harles] [Campbell], Petersburg to Ge[orge] B. Carey [Cary], Washington, 30 December 1842., 3 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 4:82)
        Wishes to recommend the post of collector to Hugh Nelson. He himself would like the position of clerkship.
    - Letters, 1843., 41 items. (Box-folder 4:83-123)
      - [Charles Campbell], to "Cousin," [c. 1843]., 2 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 4:83)
        Aleck plans to marry; sister Betty had another child; his mother teaching; he is working at the custom house.
      - Alexander S. Campbell to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 26 January 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:84)
        Has left check for public money with Mr. Maben. Postscript: E[lizabeth] M. M[aben] to Charles [Campbell] and to [Mildred Campbell]. All well and enjoying good weather.
      - C[harles] Campbell to Alex[ander] A. Campbell,28 January 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:85)
        Mr. Nelson has written Secretary of Treasury concerning his checques. Awaiting instruction.
      - John Maben, Richmond to [?], 30 January 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:86)
        Brother left recently; letter arrived after he was gone.
      - A[lexander] M[oore] Keller, Tuscumbia, [Louisiana] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 1 February 1843., 1 page. (Box-folder 4:87)
        Sympathy on death of Charles' father; family planning to move west; asks about Mr. Sutton and the revolutionary claims. Mary F[airfax] Keller to sister [Mildred Campbell]. Sympathy note; family news of other brothers and sisters.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] Henley, Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 3 February 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:88)
        Sympathy at death of Charles Campbell's father; Charles Campbell's son's estate; family news.
      - [Alexander S. Campbell], Warrenton to Charles [Campbell], 11 February 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:89)
        Asks information on settling accounts as soon as possible. Job prospects soon.
      - Kate [Beckwith], Raleigh, [North Carolina], to Anna Burdsall, Rahway, New Jersey, 12 February 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:90)
        Is spring; has gone to 16 parties; John Manly is courting her, but her parents against it.
      - [Alexander S. Campbell], Warrenton, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 20 February 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:91)
        Legal matters relating to Parker's estate. Although job prospects remain poor, he has given up thought of sailing with Captain Cocke as clerk.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] Henley, Chota, [Tennessee], to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 28 February 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:92)
        Charles Campbell's son's estate; Great scarcity of money; Family news.
      - Alex[ander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, to Charles [Campbell], 21 March 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:93)
        Sends note, giving his attorney to Charles, in matters relating to the estate of John W. Campbell.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, to Charles [Campbell], [Petersburg], 25 March 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:94)
        It would be very inconvenient for him to go to Petersburg: court session about to begin.
      - Jared Sparks, Cambridge, Massachusetts to Charles Campbell, 18 April 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:95)
        Asks him to send a copy of the Bland Papers which he has been unable to find in Boston. Also request a copy of the Westover Manuscripts, edited by Edmund Ruffin.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to Mary B. Carter, Shirley, 23 April 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:96)
        Sends her son "antiquarian collections." Enjoyed his visit to Shirley.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] Henley, Madisonville, to Charles Campbell, 8 May 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:97)
        Difficult to get money, therefore slow in remittances.
      - M[ary] B. C[arter], Shirley, to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 19 May 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:98)
        Her china arrived, and she will send money for it soon. She is feeling better, although she still suffers occasionally from headaches. Family news.
      - M[ary B.] C[arter] to M[ildred W.] Campbell, Petersburg, [After 19 May 1843]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:99)
        Encloses list of her china, including worth of pieces. Other miscellaneous items. Asks her for accounting of other expenses made on her behalf. Encloses check for $31.50, which she hopes settles everything.
      - [Jared Sparks], Cambridge, Massachusetts to Charles Campbell, 20 May 1843., 1 page. Signature clipped. AL. (Box-folder 4:100)
        Acknowledges receipt of first volume of the Bland Papers. Declares them to be more valuable than he had anticipated. Also expresses thanks to Edmund Ruffin for the Westover Manuscripts.
      - Betty [Elizabeth M. Henley], Chota, Tennessee to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 29 May 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:101)
        Has called off her wedding; Lavina Moore has not yet gotten a divorce; Mr. Barclay McGhee has been committed to a lunatic asylum; Family news.
      - Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 30 May 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:102)
        Offers his assistance in binding his book, and gives advice on how to set a price for it. Gives news of friends.
      - L. Wallazz Philadelphia, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 31 May 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:103)
        Amusing description of presenting Charles Campbell's letter to Mr. Grigg who said he would act on the matter at a "convenient season." Would promote sale of Bland Papers. Humiliating confession of poverty is fashionable. Will begin printing shop on credit. Mesmerism and Millerism growing Mormonism stationary. Theatres.
      - Announcement for Henry Howe's Historical Collections of Virginia,10 June 1843., 1 page. (Box-folder 4:104)
      - Charles Campbell Petersburg, Virginia to Cha[rle]s Hosmer, Connecticut Historical Society, 12 June 1843., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 4:105)
        Accepts honorary membership in Connecticut Historical Society.
      - J. M. Randolph, Richmond to C[harles] Campbell, 19 June 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:106)
        Letter of introduction for Henry How.
      - W. C. Banister, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, 24 June 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:107)
        Will not recommend Charles Campbell as his successor.
      - [Henry Howe?], Midlothian to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 14 July 1843., 1 page. Signature clipped. AL. (Box-folder 4:108)
        Will be traveling in eastern and western Virginia; hopes to meet him in the winter. Sends him some drawings, including a sketch of Bacon's Castle.
      - L. Wallazz, Philadelphia, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 30 July 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:109)
        Actions of Connecticut Historical Society pleasing. Regret that ignorance of Charles Campbell's deserts deprives him of similar favor in Virginia. Little acquaintance with booksellers, now in type and steroetype establishment, but will try to promote Bland Papers. Have met John F. Watson, antiquarian and author of Annals of Philadelphia, much like Charles Campbell. Will bring out 3rd ed. of Annals. Financial matters of Mr. Ruffin. Unable to dispose of type. Confused paper money Penn. Politicians emphasize "principle," "patriotism," etc., but none in actions.
      - John Tyler, Washington to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 27 August 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:110)
        Thanks him for the Bland Papers. Comments about historical materials of the Revolution.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to "my dear cousin," 28 August 1843., 2 pages. ADf. (Box-folder 4:111)
        Received letter from President Tyler marking Charles Campbell for book. Family news, engaged to be married to a young lady at school with a decent fortune. Social news.
      - A. P. Upshur, Washington to Charles Campbell, Petersburg. 8 September 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:112)
        Acknowledges receipt of the Bland Papers, one copy for himself, one for the Library of Congress.
      - Lucy D. Henry, Cub Creek, Charlotte, Virginia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 11 September 1843., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:113)
        Enjoyed reading his articles; poem, Lines in Honor of a ____ Patriot.
      - [Jared Sparkes], Cambridge, Massachusetts to Charles Campbell, 12 September 1843., 2 pages. Signature clipped. AL. (Box-folder 4:114)
        Acknowledges receipt of the Bland Papers and praises their usefulness. Expresses regret that they have not sold as many copies as expected.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, Richmond, 13 September 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:115)
        Points out several typographical errors in the September 1843 edition of the Southern Literary Messenger. Is sending some "scraps" for inclusion in the Messenger, under the title of "Virginia Antiquities." Suggests changing title of that column to "Old Mortalities." Asks for reprints of articles of his that have appeared in the Messenger so he will not have to cut them out himself.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Dolly [Lucy] D. Henry,26 September 1843., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 4:116)
        Enjoyed her letter; They are distantly related; Would like to see her manuscripts.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, to Charles [Campbell] [Petersburg], 28 September 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:117)
        Has been asked to give an address to a pro-Calhoun gathering. Has forwarded a copy of the Bland Papers to the editor of the Alexandria Gazette.
      - W. R. Drinkard, Surry County, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 30 October 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:118)
        Description of the tombstones at the Old church at the Cabin Point.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, to Charles [Campbell] [Petersburg], 14 October 1843., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:119)
        Encloses power of attorney.
      - A[bby] J. Champion, Troy, to Anna Burdsall, Rahway, New Jersey, 23 October 1843., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:120)
        Asks her to help a friend visiting New York; asks if she has read Mysteries of Paris.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg, to Alex[ander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, 25 October 1843., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:121)
        Has sent deposit to Richmond bank, settling government account. Resolves not to become involved in party politics. This may change if Calhoun is nominated.
      - E. F. W. Brownsburg, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 1 November 1843., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:122)
        Has a copy of the Bland Papers.
      - E. F. W., Brownsburg, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 26 December 1843., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:123)
        Asks for magazines.
    - Letters, 1844., 51 items. (Box 4-5)
      - 2 poems, 1844., 2 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 4:124)
      - Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut to [Charles Campbell], 2 January 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:125)
        He has been working very hard on his book National Education, but he is having difficulty finding a publisher. He is doing much work in Rhode Island, organizing their educational system.
      - Kate [Beckwith], Petersburg, Virginia to Ann Burdsall, Rahway, New Jersey, 15 January 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:126)
        Asks her to write; Is visiting her brother.
      - And[re]w Alexande r, Lexington, [Virginia] to [Charles Campbell], 20 January 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:127)
        Rehiring of slave Billy. Has been ill.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, [Virginia] to Andrew Alexander, Lexington, Virginia, 24 January 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:128)
        Will not hire his slave Billy again.
      - A. B. Guigon, Washington, to [Charles] Campbell, 27 January 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:129)
        Letter concerns Texas and the Union. Reference to Virginia Senate as "locofoco". Mention of Thomas Hart Benton's speech.
      - M[ary] K. Henley, Chota, E. Tennessee, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 28 January [1844]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:130)
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 2 February 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:131)
        Hopes her move will work out well. She is very well. Family news.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to George C. Dromgoole, House of Representatives, 2 February 1844., 3 pages. ADfS. (Box-folder 4:132)
        Appeal for Walthall's landing to remain in the port of Petersburg district.
      - J. K. Tefft, Savannah, Georgia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 17 February 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:133)
        He is trying to assemble a collection of autograph letters of men of the Revolution. He asks Campbell if he has any letters, especially of Washington and George Wythe to contribute. He offers Campbell letters of Pinckneys and others in return.
      - B[enjamin] B. Minor, Savannah, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 16 February 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:134)
        Letter of introduction of J. K. Tefft. Asks Campbell to cooperate with him.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to J. K. Tefft, Savannah, 24 February 1844., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:134)
        Acknowledges receipt of his letter and note from Benjamin Minor. Gives list of duplicate autographs he would be glad to send him. Gives names of those he wishes in exchange.
      - J. K. Tefft, Savannah to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 1 March 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:135)
        Has been quite ill. Will gladly accept autographs offered by Campbell. Gives him information on how to send them to him.
      - M[ary] C[ampbell], Shirley to Mildred Campbell, Petersburg, 5 March 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:136)
        Sends some seeds. Family news.
      - W. Simmons, W. B. Merritt, M. R. Pierce, Emory College, to [Charles Campbell], 11 March 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:137)
        Charles Campbell elected to Phi Gamma Society.
      - Arthur H[azelrigg] Henley, Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 13 March 1844., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:138)
        Money from Charles Campbell's son's estate; Disposition of the estate's slaves; Family news.
      - J. K. Tefft, Savannah to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 16 March 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:139)
        Gives list of manuscripts and autographs he is sending today in separate parcels.
      - C[harles] Campbell, Petersburg to J. K. Tefft, Savannah, 23 March 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:140)
        Acknowledges receipt of letters and autographs. Lists autographs of many Revolutionary leaders found in the Bland Papers.
      - J. K. Tefft, Savannah to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 30 March 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:141)
        Lists those letters and autographs he would appreciate having.
      - Charles [Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Mary K. Henley, Chota, Tennessee, 2 April 1844., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:142)
        Surprised at news of Elizabeth's marriage; Remembers beauty of Chota.
      - Alex[ander] S. Campbell to Charles [Campbell], 4 April 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:143)
        Acknowledges receipt of $70.00. News of William Campbell(cousin?), who is editor of St. Louis New Era.
      - L. Wallazz, Philadelphia, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 2 May 1844., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:144)
        Can't sell printing material, so is setting up shop, but poor until gets work. Now needs what sold, and didn't get the money. Hopes can get material back for non-payment, will Charles Campbell inquire? E. C. Biddle preparing to resign as director, will see him about how Bland is selling. Friends at Malbourne well, enjoying beautiful new home, but Charles Campbell must philosophize with friend not to overwork. Democrats would carry an election because Whigs all at Baltimore convention. Financially strapped, but doesn't want the people of Petersburg to know it.
      - Ar[thur] H[azelrigg] [Henley], Chota, [Tennessee] to Charles Campbell, 4 May 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:145)
        Apologizes for delay in remittances.
      - George Bancroft, Boston to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 14 May 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 4:46)
        Thanks him for a copy of the Bland Papers. Hopes he will publish other important source collections for Virginia history.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Anna B. Dudley, Tennessee, 21 May 1844., 3 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 4:147)
        Sends copy of correspondence of Col. Bland; Asks for information on Col. Bland.
      - Anna Bland Dudley, Franklin Williamson, to [Charles Campbell], 1 June 1844., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:148)
        Recounts family history and stories; Has manuscripts of history of the war in the Carolinas by Guilford Dudley.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Anna B[land] Dudley, Tennessee, 12 June 1844., 2 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 4:149)
        Thanks her for her information.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Preston Trotter, Brownsburg, Virginia, 18 June 1844., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 4:150)
        Sends notes on Campbell family genealogy.
      - M[ary] B. Carter, Shirley to M[ildred] W. Campbell, Petersburg, 9 July 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:151)
        Invites her down; There is little sickness there. Religious, church news.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Warrenton, to Charles Campbell, Richmond, 15 July [1844]. (Box-folder 4:152)
        Surprised to hear he was in Richmond, but thinks he will do well at the Customs House. Happily married now. Gave political speech. Postscript: Morly [Homer Campbell] to [Charles Campbell]. Has found a widow for Charles Campbell to marry. Invites him for a visit.
      - [Mrs. Mildred W. Campbell], Petersburg to Charles [Campbell], 20 July 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:153)
        Informing him of her sending him a trunk. Postscript: Callaway Campbell, Petersburg to [Charles Campbell] his father. News of his hen.
      - Thomas C. Reynolds, Petersburg, to [Charles Campbell], 22 July 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 4:154)
        Excuses delay in answering Charles Campbell's letter of the 12th. Hopes for help from Charles Campbell-articles. Thanks for back issues of the Statesman. Agrees with Charles Campbell's wish for less asperity in political dissensions. Reynolds has been unsparing in his editorials. Would like to be milder if policy and opponents would allow.
      - [?] to [?], 28 July 1844., 2 pages. AL. (Box-folder 4:155)
        Haunted room at Ampthill; Describes tobacco warehouse.
      - [Mrs. Mildred W. Campbell], Shirley to Charles [Campbell], 8 August 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:1)
        News of her trip to Shirley with Callaway Campbell and cousin Philip Aglett.
      - Thomas C. Reynolds, Petersburg to Charles Campbell, Richmond, 13 August 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:2)
        Received Charles Campbell's letter of the 10th. Undisposed to get into a contest with the Richmond Whig which has the advantage of wider circulation. Reynolds' first attack, abolition proceeding which might have placed disunionist Whig on defensive, were given no notice by democratic papers. Whig said no word on the proceedings. Will issue weekly paper at low price for Virginia and North Carolina to force respect from "big" papers. Requests written communication for the Republican. Should see several men about establishing Antiquarian Society.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell, Warrenton to Charles Campbell, Richmond, 9 September 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:3)
        He and Molly were disappointed at not seeing him this summer. He attended tournament at the Springs, heard address by Judge B[everly] Tucker. Losing interest in politics.
      - Anna Bland Dudley, [Tennessee] to [Charles Campbell], 14 September 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:4)
        Is sending manuscript of the war in the Carolinas for publication; is moving to Louisiana.
      - Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 14 September 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:5)
        Hope to have his book in press by November; he hopes to have it well-illustrated. Asks some questions about early Virginia history.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg to Henry Howe, [New Haven, Connecticut], 29 September 1844., 1 page. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 5:6)
        Makes corrections in his memoir of John Randolph.
      - Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, [Virginia] to Anna B. Dudley, 14 October 1844., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 5:7)
        Has received her manuscript and part is missing; suggests publication in Southern Literary Messenger.
      - M[ary] B. [Carter], Shirley to Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg, 15 October 1844., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:8)
        Hopes [her son] Charles [Carter] is doing well with his studies. Will send money for him. Charles Campbell has given her a copy of his book.
      - Alex[ander] S. Campbell, Warrenton to Charles [Campbell], November 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:9)
        Business matters still referring to settling of father's estate. Will pay Charles all he owes him.
      - Henry Howe, New Haven to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, Virginia, 6 November 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:10)
        Thanks him for Randolph portrait; experts to get his work published soon.
      - Charles Campbell, Richmond to Henry Howe, [New Haven, Connecticut], 15 November 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:11)
        Will endeavor to send the information on recent political history he asked for. He is glad James K. Polk has been elected, even though he feels sorry for Henry Clay, and his Whig friends.
      - Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, 20 November 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:12)
        He has already received the requested information on recent Virginia political history from another source. As a Whig, he is sorry that Polk has defeated Clay, but is not discouraged.
      - Edmund Ruffin, Marlbourne, to [Charles Campbell][?], 20 November 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:13)
        Pertains to an intended visit of Campbell to Ruffin. Mentions defeat of Henry Clay.
      - W[illia]m Spotswood Fontaine, to Charles Campbell [Richmond, Virginia], 21 November 1844., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 5:14)
        Asks for papers to read before their trip to Gloucester.
      - Henry Howe, New Haven to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 23 November 1844., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 5:15)
        Has written an article entitled Life In Western Virginia, describing everyday frontier life. Asks Campbell to write an article for him on life in Eastern Virginia as a comparison piece.
      - Thomas C. Reynolds, Richmond, to [Charles Campbell], 24 November 1844., 1 page. ALC. (Box-folder 5:16)
        Reynolds no longer edits the Republican. Returned to Richmond and attends to practice. No time for paper which Charles Campbell suggests, doubts would be successful alongside The Messenger. Would be willing to cultivate Charles Campbell's acquaintance.
      - Edmund Ruffin, Marlbourne, to [Charles Campbell], 16 December 1844. (Box-folder 5:17)